# Emin Can Oguz

Istanbul/Turkey emincanoguz11@gmail.com emincanoguz11.github.io

## **ABOUT ME**

As a data engineer with 3 years of experience, I specialize in designing, building, and maintaining high-performance data systems. I have experience managing large-scale data pipelines, implementing streaming solutions, and optimizing costs and queries within clusters. In particular, I have successfully managed data infrastructure for multiple Black Friday events, delivering reliable performance and insights to stakeholders.

### **EDUCATION**

Maltepe University- Software Engineering (2016-2021)

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Hepsiburada - Data Engineer (April 2021 - Present)

I developed a Data Mesh pipeline for all teams, as well as a Data pipeline. Additionally, I implemented a streaming job utilizing real-time technologies, and managed a cluster exceeding 10PB. To further support my teams, I also created Airflow pipelines. I focused on optimizing costs and queries within the cluster. To obtain a data engineering position with a focus on optimizing data pipelines and infrastructure for high-traffic events, such as Black Friday.

## Doctorla aka Online Saglikcim - Junior Data Scientist (April 2020 – Jan 2021)

As a junior data scientist with a background in machine learning, I have experience
developing and deploying NLP models using Tensorflow. I am passionate about
using my skills to solve real-world problems, particularly in the healthcare domain. I
have experience working with large-scale datasets and utilizing advanced
techniques to extract insights and create predictive models.

## RemoteTeam.com - Junior Data Scientist (May 2020 - Jan 2021)

 As a Junior data scientist with a background in recommendation systems, I have experience deploying algorithms to generate personalized recommendations for users. I have experience working with large-scale datasets and utilizing advanced techniques to extract insights and create predictive models.

### Yesil Science - Intern (April 2020 – June 2020)

• I developed Mandarin project for scoring healtcare using Machine Learning.

### **SKILLS**

Python, Java, ,Scala, C#, SQL, NoSQL, Cloud Technologies (AWS,Google Cloud), Prometheus, Apache Druid, Apache Spark, Apache Hadoop, Apache Kafka, RabbitMQ, Linux, Kubernetes, Docker, Gitlab CI/CD, Jenkins, Tensorflow, Spark NLP, Scikit-Learn, Google BigQuery, Google Cloud Storage. Apache Airflow, DBT, Amundsen. Datahub, MongoDB